<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="Updates.xslt"?>
<updates xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="Updates.xsd">
	<application>
		<title>Microsoft XML Notepad</title>
		<location>https://lovettsoftwarestorage.blob.core.windows.net/downloads/XmlNotepad/Updates.xml</location>
		<download>https://lovettsoftwarestorage.blob.core.windows.net/downloads/XmlNotepad/readme.htm</download>
		<installer>https://microsoft.github.io/XmlNotepad/install/</installer>
		<history>https://github.com/microsoft/XmlNotepad/blob/master/src/Updates/Updates.xml</history>
		<frequency>1.00:00:00</frequency>
	</application>
  <version number="2.8.0.40">
    <bug>Fix handling of files in recent files list that no longer exist.</bug>
    <bug>Fix handling of files that are renamed to .bak by another editor.</bug>
    <bug>Fix bugs in Find/Replace clicking Replace repeatedly was broken.  Added unit tests to cover this case.</bug>
    <bug>Remove Help/Index since it went to the same place as Help/Content.</bug>
  </version>
  <version number="2.8.0.39">
    <bug>
      Fix bug in XSL transform of documents fetched from http location.
      Add unit test for this case.
    </bug>
  </version>
  <version number="2.8.0.38">
    <bug>
      Fix bug in rendering large documents using default stylesheet.
    </bug><bug>
      Fix layout bug of toolbar on high DPI screens.      
    </bug>
  </version>
  <version number="2.8.0.36">
    <bug>
      Fix bug in support for non webview2 case.</bug>
    <bug>
      Automatically register XML notepad with Open With dialog.
    </bug>
  </version>
	<version number="2.8.0.35">
		<bug>
			Added support for Chromium based WebView2 control for XSLT output.
			You can download this from https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-edge/webview2/.
		</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.33">
		<bug>
			Ctrl+A short cut for SaveAs interferes with text editing, so removed Ctrl+A shortcut from SaveAs.</bug>
    <bug>
      One more fix to "openFileDialog1" default file name on schema dialog.
    </bug>
    <bug>
			Fix tooltip in options dialog Default Text Editor option.
		</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.32">
		<feature>
			Add user settable default text editor option for View Source.
		</feature>
		<bug>
			Fix Schema dialog so it doesn't set filename to "openFileDialog1".</bug>
  <bug>
			Fix View/Source on http files (uses temp file).
		</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.31">
		<bug>
			Fix memory usage bug to do with loading huge XML files.</bug>
  <bug>
			Report XSLT transform times in the status bar.
		</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.30">
		<feature>
			Enable [github issue #86](https://github.com/microsoft/XmlNotepad/issues/86) - allow an XmlNotepad.settings
			file to be found in the same folder as XmlNotepad.exe and use this instead of the one in %LOCALAPPDATA%.
		</feature>
		<feature>
			See [github issue #86](https://github.com/microsoft/XmlNotepad/issues/86) - add a browse button to help
			set XSLT output file name.
		</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.29">
		<bug>
			Fix [github issue #87](https://github.com/microsoft/XmlNotepad/issues/87) - bug in finding text in attribute values
			and add unit tests to cover this.  Also fixed problem with stepping through multiple matches using F3 in one big paragraph.
		</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.28">
		<feature>Thanks to Austin Wise for adding High DPI scaling which makes the fonts a lot less blurry on high DPI screens.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.27">
		<feature>Minor fixes to XML stats output got github issues #76 and #77.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.26">
		<feature>Provide a way to disable google analytics before installing XML Notepad.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.24">
		<feature>Check XML diff files are different files.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.23">
		<feature>Add ability to import HTML files and convert them to XML using SgmlReader.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.19">
		<feature>Add optional google analytics so we can get an idea of usage.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.18">
		<bug>Fix Dark Theme options editing and add new color for text editor background.</bug>
		<bug>Fix performance bug to do with expanding too many nodes on save and on find.</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.14">
		<feature>Fix bug in current file address combobox.  Start implementing stylecop code cleanups.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.13">
		<feature>Sync offline help so it matches the online help, fix some typos and add more info to options dialog help text.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.12">
		<feature>Add auto-completion in location combobox and increased history to 1000 filenames.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.11">
		<feature>Add support for "Dark" theme colors and a way to easily switch between light and dark theme.</feature>
		<feature>Add transparent icons that look good on dark backgrounds</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.10">
		<bug>Fix F1 help.</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.9">
		<bug>Fix locked file bug after doing xml comparison (github issue# 44).</bug>
		<bug>Fix BOM option so it is honored on XSLT output files also (github issue# 46).</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.7">
		<bug>Fix problem with TLS 1.2 by upgrading to .NET Framework 4.7.2</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.8.0.0">
		<feature>Merge fixes from shadolight and add options that control how XmlDiff behaves.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.7.1.21">
		<feature>Merge change by Vincent Lepape which adds a new MaximumValueLength setting.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.7.1.18">
		<bug>Fix some layout bugs that happen when system font size is increased beyond 100%.</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.7.1.17">
		<feature>Add output file field to XSL Output tab which fixes problems with relative links in the XSLT output.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.7.1.16">
		<bug>Thanks to Steve Romanow for fixing some old codeplex URL references.</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.7.1.12">
		<feature>Add XML stats under View menu.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.7.1.8">
		<feature>Add line numbers on the XML diff output.</feature>
		<bug>Fix navigation of differences</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.7.1.6">
		<feature>Add ability to import *.csv files.</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.7.1">
		<feature>Add new option to allow you to save XML files without the UTF-8 byte order mark.</feature>
		<feature>Add SHA 256 digital signature for stronger security.</feature>
		<bug>Fix regression in loading xml from http</bug>
		<bug>Fix regression in copy &amp; paste noedes</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.7">
		<feature>Control over handling of long lines.  Added new options "Maximum Line Length" and "Autoformat Long Lines"</feature>
	</version>
	<version number="2.6">
		<feature>Upgrade to .NET 4.0</feature>
		<feature>Add support for picking different languages for Dynamic Help from xsd:documentation.</feature>
		<feature>Add ability to select default File Associations for the app</feature>
		<bug>Find dialog should not always be "top most" window on the desktop</bug>
		<bug>Make text in ErrorList window "word wrap" so you can read long error messages</bug>
		<bug>Fix NormalizeText bug in XmlDiff reported by GalacticCowboy</bug>
		<bug>Fix bug in how schemaLocation attribute is resolved so that validation results are more predictable</bug>
		<bug>Add inner exception detail to error reporting, sometimes this provides more information about the error.</bug>
		<bug>Fix XML compare for files containing greek characters as reported by Birbilis.</bug>
		<bug>Fix synchronization of vertical position across tree view and text view.</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.5">
		<feature>Add Proxy Authentication support</feature>
		<feature>Add formatting options</feature>
		<feature>Switch to out-of-process unit testing using IAccessibility only</feature>
		<bug>Unhandled exception on invalid syntax for xml declaration</bug>
		<bug>Unable to reset splitter if accidently moved off screen</bug>
		<bug>XSLT transform is not reloaded when it is changed on disk</bug>
		<bug>Using a stylesheet containing a DTD doesn't work</bug>
		<bug>Find by XPath should show all namespaces prefixes in scope</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.4">
		<bug>Fixed location of updates.xml page so auto-updater works properly</bug>
		<bug>Fixed problems in incremental search (CTRL+I) giving up too soon</bug>
		<bug>Fixed layout to remove margins around the TabControls and prettied up the XSLT output tab</bug>
		<bug>Fixed Find (CTRL+F), Copy (CTRL+C) and View Source commands in XSLT output window</bug>
		<bug>Fixed options dialog resize bug</bug>
		<bug>Fix null reference exception on Window/New Window when window is empty</bug>
		<bug>Turn off reload loading of previously opened file</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.3">
		<feature>Added "change to" menu for changing node types</feature>
		<feature>Added support for XInclude</feature>
		<feature>Added DynamicHelp tab and Tooltips based on xsd:annotations</feature>
		<feature>Added [next|prev] links to XmlDiff output window for navigating changes</feature>
		<feature>
			Added support for loading XML documents containing illegal characters, reporting
			these errors in the error list
		</feature>
		<feature>Added "Export Errors" option for saving contents of the error list to a file</feature>
		<feature>Added "Goto Definition" option for navigating to XIncludes and XSD schemas</feature>
		<feature>
			Added keyboard accelerators for inserting a child element (Ctrl+Insert) and
			a child attribute (Alt+Insert)
		</feature>
		<feature>Added simple auto-updater to help user know when a new version is available</feature>
		<feature>Added navigation combo box for easy entry of http file locations</feature>
		<feature>Improved unit test coverage to 87%</feature>
		<bug>Fixed bug in task list when different sort order is in effect</bug>
		<bug>Fixed bug in scroll bar not recalculating properly</bug>
		<bug>Fixed focus issues with intellisense window</bug>
		<bug>Clear undo stack when new file is loaded</bug>
		<bug>Fixed a few null reference exceptions</bug>
		<bug>Fixed bug in restoring window size when window is closed in minimized or maximized state</bug>
		<bug>Fixed xsi:type attribute validation (properly this time!)</bug>
		<bug>Fixed performance of changing namespace values on a large document</bug>
		<bug>
			Made it so that Escape key closes intellisense drop down window without cancelling the edit
			which allows you to edit a value that is not in the list - which is important for simpleType unions
		</bug>
		<bug>Fixed insert of processing instruction named 'xml'</bug>
		<bug>Fixed schema cache when targetNamespace is changed</bug>
		<bug>Fix performance and layout of find dialog</bug>
		<bug>Track edits to xml-stylesheet processing instruction so XSLT output tab stays in sync</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.2">
		<bug>Fixed Compare Files...</bug>
		<bug>Fixed file open and save as filters so the dialogs work properly when you select a different file type</bug>
	</version>
	<version number="2.1">
		<feature>Added keyboard accelerators for find again (F3) and reverse find (SHIFT+F3)</feature>
		<feature>
			Added support for loading IXmlBuilder and IXmlEditor implementations
			from different assemblies using new vs:assembly attribute
		</feature>
		<feature>Made source code localizable by moving all error messages and dialog strings to .resx files</feature>
		<feature>Added a default XSL transform</feature>
		<feature>New icons, a play on the Vista "Notepad" icons</feature>
		<bug>Fixed install on Windows Vista machines</bug>
		<bug>Performance of expand node when validating</bug>
		<bug>Fixed bug where changed schemas and transforms were not being re-loaded</bug>
		<bug>Fixed spurious warnings about file being changed on disk</bug>
		<bug>Fixed handling of very long text nodes</bug>
		<bug>Fixed round trip of DTD content in &lt;!DOCTYPE&gt; tags</bug>
		<bug>Fixed validation of elements with xsi:type attributes</bug>
		<bug>Scroll bar not updating when node expanded/collapsed in some cases</bug>
		<bug>Tree view needs horizontal scrollbar</bug>
		<bug>
			When Microsoft XML Notepad is minimized and file changes on disk, the file reload prompt is
			confusing -- Microsoft XML Notepad should be restored first
		</bug>
		<bug>XSL output window should pick up new xsl-transform based on input document</bug>
		<bug>Fixed unhandled exception when closing a group of XML notepad windows</bug>
		<bug>Added registration of "Edit" action for .xml file extension</bug>
	</version>
</updates>